Guide to the Susan Howe Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Susan Howe papers
1894-2008
1956-2008
YCAL MSS 338
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
15.50
(23 boxes) + 9 broadside folders
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Susan Howe in the course of her activities as a poet, author, and teacher, and primarily documents Howe's literary career from 1998 to 2008. Material includes correspondence with poets, authors, artists, and musicians; drafts and manuscripts of published poetry collections, including The Midnight, Kidnapped, and Pierce-Arrow, and other writings; notebooks and diaries; teaching and research material; artwork; and family and personal papers.
Howe, Susan, 1937-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 31(electronic document): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 21-30 (Series IV: Art Work): Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Box 32 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Susan Howe
Susan Howe was born in 1937 in Boston, Massachusetts. She is the author of several books of poems and two volumes of criticism. Her poetry collections include: The Midnight (2003), Kidnapped (2002), The Europe of Trusts (2002), Pierce-Arrow (1999), Frame Structures: Early Poems 1974-1979 (1996), The Nonconformist's Memorial (1993), The Europe of Trusts: Selected Poems (1990), and Singularities (1990).
Since 1989 she has been a professor of English at the State University of New York at Buffalo, and is currently the Samuel P. Capen Chair of Poetry and the Humanities. She was elected a Chancellor of The Academy of American Poets in 2000. Susan Howe lives in Guilford, Connecticut.
Biographical information is drawn from Poets.org.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Susan Howe in the course of her activities as a poet, author, and teacher, and primarily documents Howe's literary career from 1998 to 2008. Material includes correspondence with poets, authors, artists, and musicians; drafts and manuscripts of published poetry collections, including The Midnight, Kidnapped, and Pierce-Arrow, and other writings; notebooks and diaries; teaching and research material; artwork; and family and personal papers. Correspondents include: Rae Armantrout, Dennis Barone, Samuel Beckett, Susan Bee, Charles Bernstein, Anne Carson, Norma Cole, Robert Creeley, Simon Cutts, Rachel Blau DuPlessis, Alec Finlay, Dominique Fourcade, Lyn Hejinian, Fanny Howe, Devin Johnston, J. C. C. Mays, Maureen Owen, Michael Palmer, Kristin Prevallet, Bernard Rival, Leslie Scalapino, Susan Stewart, Cole Swensen, John Taggart, Erica Van Horn, Rosmarie Waldrop, and Elizabeth Willis.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Correspondence, 1956-2008. II. Writings, 1894-2007. III. Notebooks and Diaries, 1984-2007. IV. Professional Papers, 1961-2007. V. Family and Personal Papers, circa 1916-2001. VI. Art Work, 1958-1973.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Born digital; Drawings (visual works); Electronic documents; Armantrout, Rae, 1947-; Barone, Dennis; Beckett, Samuel, 1906-1989; Bee, Susan; Bernstein, Charles, 1950-; Carson, Anne, 1950-; Cole, Norma, 1945-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005; Cutts, Simon, 1944-; DuPlessis, Rachel Blau; Finlay, Alec, 1966-; Fourcade, Dominique; Hejinian, Lyn; Howe, Fanny, 1940-; Howe, Susan, 1937-; Johnston, Devin, 1970-; Mays, J. C. C.; Owen, Maureen, 1943-; Palmer, Michael, 1943-; Prevallet, Kristin; Rival, Bernard; Scalapino, Leslie; Stewart, Susan, 1952-; Swensen, Cole, 1955-; Taggart, John, 1942-; Van Horn, Erica, 1954-; Waldrop, Rosmarie, 1935-; Willis, Elizabeth
- Correspondence, 1956-2008; Series I; (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged into two subseries: General Correspondence and Email Correspondence (printouts). Correspondents overlap between the two subseries.
  - General Correspondence, 1956-2008
    Arranged alphabetically according to correspondent, reflecting the order in which the material was received by the library.
    - A-L, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1999-2001 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Mary, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Aden, Etel, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Albon, George, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Chris, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - American Poetry Review, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Armantrout, Rae, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Askenase, Alicia (Walt Whitman Art Center), 2003 (Box 1)
    - Back, Rachel, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Bair, Deidre, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Baird, Ansie, 1998-2005 (Box 1)
    - Barone, Dennis, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Beckett, Samuel, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Bee, Susan, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Belek, Rubyn (Hartford Friends & Enemies of Wallace Stevens), 2003 (Box 1)
    - Bennett, Dianne (Box 1)
    - Berlowitz, Leslie (American Academy of Arts & Sciences), 2003 (Box 1)
    - Bernstein, Charles, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
    - Bertaccini, Joan, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
    - Bertholf, Robert, 2004-2005 (Box 1)
    - Bervin, Jen (Box 1)
    - Billitteri, Carla & Friedlander, Benjamin, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Breverman, Harvey, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Butrick, Lyn, 1999 (Box 1)
    - California Institute of Technology, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Cameron, Sharon, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Campbell, Sarah, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
    - Carlson, David, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Carson, Anne, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Caserio, Robert, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
    - Casey, Perry Reddin, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
    - Chicago Review, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Cleveland State University, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Cole, Barbara, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Cole, Norma, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Coleman, Winifred (Saint Joseph College), 2003 (Box 1)
    - Collis, Steve, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Creeley Robert, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Cunningham, Brent, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Cutts, Simon, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Davidson, Michael, 1998 (Box 1)
    - DeGraw, Sharon, 2004 (Box 1)
    - DuPlessis, Rachel Blau, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Dydo, Ulla, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Eikvold, Jan (?), 2003 (Box 1)
    - Eller, Jon, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Epler, Barbara, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Esdale, Logan, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Fattal, Simone (Box 1)
    - Fernie, Ewan, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Feshbach, Sidney, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Finlay, Alec, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Folger Shakespeare Library, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Fondation Cartier, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Fourcade, Dominique, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Fourcade, Dominique - Vol. I, 2001-2003 (Box 1)
    - Fourcade, Dominique - Vol. II, 1998-2008 (Box 1)
    - Foust, Graham, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Fox, Peggy (New Directions), 1998 (Box 1)
    - Frazier, Adrian, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Fredman, Steve, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Freitag, Kornelia, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Furbush, Margaret, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Gackstetter, Michael (Harbor Towers Condominium), 2003 (Box 1)
    - Gallagher, Kristen, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Gander, Forrest (Box 1)
    - Gardner, Tom, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Gerber, Natalie, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Gibson, Margaret, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Gilbert, Alan, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Gizzi, Peter, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Gonzalez, Alfonso & Mirta, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Greiner, William, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Grinnell, Tracy, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Groarke, Vona (Box 1)
    - Grubbs, David, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Guthrie, Camille, 1999-2006 (Box 1)
    - Hafif, Marcia, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Hejinian, Lyn, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Heuving, Jeanee (Box 1)
    - Howe, Fanny, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Howe, Mary Manning (Box 1)
    - Huang, Yunte, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Interim, 1998 (Box 1)
    - The Iowa Review, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Jenks, Philip, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Jilka, Lucy & Collier, Danny, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Johnston, Brigid, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Johnston, Devin, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Jordon, Josephine (Box 1)
    - Joyce, Lisa, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Kasemets, Udo, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Kelly Writers House, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Ketther, Ken, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Killian, Kevin, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Knowlson, Jim, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Lewin, Anya (Box 1)
    - Lomke, Evander (Continuum Books), 2005 (Box 1)
    - Lurie, Alison, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Lynch, Deidre, 1999 (Box 1)
    - MacCarthy, Lavinia (Reddin) (Box 2)
    - Mackenzie, Cindy, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Madden, Ed & Marian, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Magee, Michael, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Manning, Susan, 1956-1957, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Mao, Doug, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Mark, Alison, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Mason-Morgan, Susanne, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Mays, J. C. C., 1997-2002 (Box 2)
    - McGann, Jerry, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Memorial Art Gallery, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Mengham, Rod, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Menikoff, Barry, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Miller, Cristanne, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Miller, Linda, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Miller, Sandra & Lau, David (Eds., 1913 - A Journal of Forms), 2003 (Box 2)
    - Moeller, Achim (Achim Moeller Fine Art), 1998 (Box 2)
    - Montgomery, Will, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Mullen, Harryette, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Nanfito, Bryanne, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Nelson, Gale, 2001 (Box 2)
    - New Directions, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Newth Harrison, Rebecca, 1999-2004 (Box 2)
    - Newton, Jere, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Norman, Howard, 2003 (Box 2)
    - O'Brien, Michael, 2001 (Box 2)
    - O'Driscoll, Michael, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Overbeck, Lois, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Optic Nerve, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Owen, Maureen, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
    - Palattella, John, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Palmer, Michael, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
    - Pankey, Eric (Box 2)
    - Pelton, Ted, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Perloff, Marjorie, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Persson, Goy, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Possick, Stan, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Prevallet, Kristin, 1999-2003 (Box 2)
    - Putnam, James, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Quartermain, Peter, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Quaytman, Rebecca, 1998; 2005; 2 (Box 2)
    - Quinn, Alice, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Reality Street Editions, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Reed, Brian, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Revell, Donald, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Richards, Sarah, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
    - Rival, Bernard, 1998-2001 (Box 2)
    - Sandelius, Håkan, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Scalapino, Leslie, 2002-2004 (Box 2)
    - Schlesinger, Kyle (Box 2)
    - Schmitz, Neil, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Selerie, Gavin, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Shaw, Lytle, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Sheard, Wendy Stedman, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Sherman, S. (Box 2)
    - Sieburth, Richard, 1999; 2005 (Box 2)
    - Silkeberg, Marie, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Simon, Cathy, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Sobin, Gustaf, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Spahr, Juliana, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Starr, Polly Thayer, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Diana Childers, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Steensen, Sasha, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Diana, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Susan, 1998-2003 (Box 2)
    - Taggart, John, 1998-2007 (Box 2)
    - Swensen, Cole, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Tamminen, Suzanna, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Tichy, Susan, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Tyrell, Michael, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Ullén, Jan, 1999 (Box 2)
    - University at Buffalo (SUNY), 2002-2004 (Box 2)
    - Van Gogh's Ear, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Van Horn, Erica, 2001-2005 (Box 2)
    - Vilgrain, Benédicte, 1996-2000 (Box 2)
    - Vogler, Thomas, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
    - Von Schlegell, Lisa (Box 2)
    - Von Schlegell, Mark, 1998-2001 (Box 2)
    - Warren, Charles, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Waldrop, Rosmarie, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
    - Warren, Rosanna, 2002-2004 (Box 2)
    - Werner, Marta (Box 2)
    - Wexner Center for the Arts, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Wilcox, Jonathan, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Williams, Tyrone (Box 2)
    - Willis, Elizabeth, 1998-2003 (Box 2)
    - Zawacki, Andrew, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Misc - Indeterminate unfiled M-Z, 1990s-2000s (Box 2)
  - Email Correspondence (printouts), 1999-2008
    - Academy of American Poets, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Alexander, Charles, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Alexander, Christopher, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Ali, Kazim, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Ashbery, John, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Austin, Nathan, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Ayres, Ian, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Back, Rachel, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Bailey, Matthew, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Barone, Dennis, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Bee, Susan, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Bennett, Dianne, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Bennett, Stephanie, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Berk, Ekrem Serdar, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Bernstein, Charles, 2000-2005 (Box 3)
    - Bessa, Sergio, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Bizzini, Chantal, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Brossard, Olivier, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Buelens, Geert, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Callan, Ron, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Caserio, Robert, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Clay, Steve, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Cohen, Alicia, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Coker, Karen, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Cole, Barbara, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - Conte, Joseph, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Craig, John, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Creeley, Robert, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - Cutts, Simon, 2003-2005 (Box 3)
    - Davis, Alex, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Dean, Tim, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Deming, Richard, 2002 (Box 3)
    - De Tienne, Andre, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Dick, Jennifer, 2003-2007 (Box 3)
    - Doty, Mark, 2008 (Box 3)
    - Drucker, Johanna, 2000-2002 (Box 3)
    - Dydo, Ulla, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Ellenberger, Pat, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - Eller, Jon, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Emerson, Lori, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Epler, Barbara, 2001-2003 (Box 3)
    - Esdale, Logan, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Evans, Steven, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Finch, Zack, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Finnegan, Lizzie, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Fourcade, Dominique, 2004-2008 (Box 3)
    - Foust, Graham, 2001-2003 (Box 3)
    - Freitag, Kornelia, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Friedlander, Ben, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Gardner, Tom, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Garforth, Julian, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Gatten, David, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Gray, Lisa, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Grubbs, David, 2003-2006 (Box 3)
    - Guy, Arielle, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Hare, Gwen, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Hare, Peter, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
    - Hawkins, Stephanie, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Hejinian, Lyn, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Herrey, Antony, 2002-2008 (Box 3)
    - Heuving, Jeanne, 2000-2003 (Box 3)
    - Hollister, William, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Hollywood, Amy, 2008 (Box 3)
    - Horne, Philip, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Houser, Nathan, 2008 (Box 3)
    - Howe, Fanny, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Huang, Yunte, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Johnson, Holly, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Joyce, Trevor, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Kim, Myung mi, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Kinsella, John, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Klein, Julia, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Konkol, Margaret, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Korsmeyer, Carolyn, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Liebling, Rachel, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Lynch, Deidre, 2001-2003 (Box 3)
    - Lynch, Kathryn, 2007 (Box 3)
    - Mackey, Nathaniel, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Martin, Chris, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Mays, J. C. C., 2001-2007 (Box 3)
    - McCarthy, Conor, 2003 (Box 3)
    - McGann, Jerome, 1999-2007 (Box 3)
    - Middleton, Peter, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Miller, Cristanne, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Mitchell, Domhnall, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Moestrup, Mette, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Montgomery, Will, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Nevens, Barbara, 2003 (Box 4)
    - New, Elisa, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Nicholls, Peter, 2003-2006 (Box 4)
    - O'Brien, George, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Olov, Jan, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
    - O'Malley, Cormac, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Overbeck, Lois, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Owen, Maureen, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Perloff, Marjorie, 2002-2004 (Box 4)
    - Poetics Program business, 2002-2004 (Box 4)
    - Quinn, Jeanne Follansbee, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Reed, Brian, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Richardson, Joan, 2007-2008 (Box 4)
    - Rival, Bernard, 2001-2003 (Box 4)
    - Rosen, Julia, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Schmitz, Neil, 2001-2003 (Box 4)
    - Selerie, Gavin, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Skinner, Jonathan, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Spence, Sarah, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Smith, Valerie, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Spahr, Juliana, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Steensen, Sasha, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Stewart, Susan, 1999-2008 (Box 4)
    - Still, Colin, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Stowe, William, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Swensen, Cole, 2001-2003 (Box 4)
    - Tedlock, Dennis, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Tyrell, Michael, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Vilgrain, Bénédicte, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Voigt, Ellen, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Von Schlegell, Mark, 2002-2004 (Box 4)
    - Waldrop, Rosmarie, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Walt Whitman Arts Center, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Warren, Charles, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Warren, Rosanna, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Washburn, Michael, 2008 (Box 4)
    - Weinberger, Eliot, 2001-2003 (Box 4)
    - Weinstein, Norm, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Werner, Marta, 2006 (Box 4)
    - White, Ted, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Wichelns, Kathryn, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Willis, Elizabeth, 2002; 2006 (Box 4)
    - Wing, Virginia, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Wright, Rebecca, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Zabawski, Hannah, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Zucker, Rachel, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Longenbach, Jim, 2005 (Box 4)
    - "Letters from Susan Howe", 2000-2003 (Box 4)
    - "Ask Susan About", 2000-2007 (Box 4)
    - "Misc / Non-Correspondence", 2002 (Box 4)
    - "Can't Identify Sender / email", 2001 (Box 4)
- Writings, 1894-2007; Series II; (7 boxes)
  Arranged into two subseries: Major Works and Other Writings, based how the material was organized when received by the library.
  General note
  File titles have been transcribed from original folders.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 32 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Major Works, 1894-2007
    - Pierce-Arrow (1999)
      - Practicism & Ruckenfigur 1997-1998 (Box 5)
      - MS Copy of Practicism & Ruckenfigur (later Pierce Arrow) (Box 5)
      - Finals of Practicism & Ruckenfigur I Could Not Make My Mind Up Over (Box 5)
      - Winter [1998?] MS work @ humanities Center, Stanford / early Pierce Arrow, circa 1998 (Box 5)
      - N[ew] D[irections] MS 1997 / Pierce Arrow (Box 5)
      - Pierce Arrow MS for New Directions, 1998 (Box 5)
      - Summer 1998 for Pierce Arrow (Box 5)
        Related Archival Materials note
        See: Series VIII: Computer Files, Box 23.
      - Pierce Arrow, book mockup, 1998 (Box 5)
      - Background Material on Charles Sanders Pierce, circa 2000 (Box 5)
        Scope and Contents
        Includes photocopies of Charles Sanders Pierce's published and unpublished notebooks, manuscripts, writings and letters.
        Related Materials
        There is an audiocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 32.
      - Interview with Richard S. Robin, Pierce material (audiocassette), 2000 August 7; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002104614608)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        This audiocassette is related to a folder of material titled "Background Material on Charles Sanders Pierce" in Box 5.
      - Final MS Pierce Arrow summer 1998 (Box 5)
      - Final for Peter [Glassgold] [of Pierce Arrow] 9/9/98, 1998 (Box 5)
      - Pierce Arrow final corrections, N[ew] D[irections MS (Box 5)
      - Translation - Sergio Bessa / Pierce Arrow, 2002 (Box 5)
    - The Midnight (2003)
      - Versions of 'Scare Quotes' [later Midnight] (Box 5)
      - Beginnings of Preterient / Midnight (Box 5)
      - Perterient first versions (Box 5)
      - Work on Preterient (Box 5)
      - Preterient / MD MS in correct order, 2000 (Box 6)
      - From Preterient", published in Conjunctions, 2000 (Box 6)
      - Work on 'The Midnight' (Box 6)
      - Work on 'The Midnight' (Box 6)
      - Drafts of Midnight - I (Box 6)
      - Drafts of Midnight - II (Box 6)
      - Misc. Poems - Midnight? (Box 6)
      - MS - Midnight, summer 2002 early version (Box 6)
      - The ND final MS of Midnight, 2002 (Box 6)
      - Photos for Midnight - New Directions, taken by Peter Hare and Susan Howe, 2000-2002; 5 (Box 6)
      - List of Illustrations for Midnight by Barbara Epler (Box 6)
      - Copy of photo, notes for Midnight (Box 6)
      - MS of Midnight, book mockup, 2003 (Box 6)
      - Source material, annotated books
        - Saint Teresa, by Rev. W. Fairweather and E.C. Jack, undated (Box 7)
          Includes an obituary for Susan Howe's maternal grandmother, Susan Manning, pasted onto an end sheet; a dedication to Susan Howe from her mother, Mary (né Manning) Howe; various marginal notes and ephemera; a letter which has been inserted into the book block; a newspaper photo of Samuel Beckett which has been tipped in; and a photograph assumed to be of Susan Howe's grandmother, Susan Manning, dated 1931.
        - The Irish Songbook, edited by Alfred Perceval Graves, T. Fisher Unwin, 1895 (Box 7)
        - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland, by Lewis Carroll, Macmillan and Co., 1899 (Box 7)
          Includes several newspaper clippings tipped in.
        - The Master of Ballantrae: A Winter's Tale by Robert Louis Stevenson, Cassell and Company, 1894 (Box 7)
        - Later Poems by W.B. Yeats, Macmillan and Co., 1924 (Box 8)
          Includes a dedication to Mary (né Manning) Howe, Susan Howe's mother; and various notes laid in.
    - Bed Hangings (2001)
      - Bed Hangings Summer 1999 (Box 9)
      - Variant summer 1999 Bed Hangings (Box 9)
      - Work on Bed Hangings preface, 2000 (Box 9)
      - Bed Hangings, 2000 (Box 9)
        Includes illustrations by Susan Bee.
      - Bed Hangings [Unquiet Grave] material, 2001 (Box 9)
      - Bed Hangings (Box 9)
    - Other details - Kidnapped and Bed Hangings (Box 9)
    - MS 2001: New Directions MS, printout - Bed Hangings prose section, with corrections so far, July 2007 (Box 9)
    - N[ew] D[irections] MS Before Binding (Box 9)
      Includes three separate sections: 'Four Ducks on a Pond", "I park my car in Harvard yard..." and "Kidnapped".
    - Four Ducks on a Pond (Box 9)
    - List of Illustrations, Other Notes (Box 9)
      Includes material relating to Bed Hangings, Scare Quotes, Through Meinong's Mirror and Preterient.
    - Kidnapped (2002)
      - Kidnapped early version ['Scandza'] (Box 9)
      - Kidnapped earlier version (Box 9)
      - Kidnapped MS (Box 9)
      - Kidnapped MS (Box 9)
      - Copy of Simon [Cutts] proofed MS [Kidnapped], 2002 (Box 9)
        Includes a letter with edits by Simon Cutts, as well as a book mockup and handwritten markings.
      - Simon [Cutts] 4C [Kidnapped], 2002 (Box 9)
      - Simon [Cutts] 4A complete [Kidnapped, other?] (Box 9)
      - Simon [Cutts] 4B Meinong's Mirror (Box 9)
    - "Greensleeves", circa 2003 (Box 9)
      Includes a proposed unpublished manuscript that was later incorporated into Souls of the Labadie Tract; and a book mockup with handwritten markings.
  - Other Writings, 1989-2007
    - Notes and Ideas while writing Melville's Marginalia, 1989 (Box 9)
      Includes approximately fifty pages of typed sheets and photocopies, some marked "not used".
    - Philadelphia spring/winter, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Copies of work Philadelphia, 1990 (Box 9)
    - "Marker" Sans Soleil essay, 4 (Box 9)
    - Work for Ether/Either, Fall 1996 (Box 9)
    - Ether/Either - Charles essay version, circa 1996 (Box 9)
    - Some Notes for "Framed Structures" essay, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Version of New D[irections] new work sent to Peter ---- July 1997 (Box 9)
    - Summer 1998 MS of Arisbe (Box 9)
    - Untitled MS [Arisbe] for N[ew] D[irections] / Stanford, circa 1998 (Box 9)
    - Susan Howe New Directions MS [Arisbe] Stanford 1998 (Box 9)
    - Copy of Pierce talk in Profession magazine, 1998 (Box 10)
    - Vancouver Dickenson piece [essay by SH], 1998 (Box 10)
    - Work on Claude Royet-Journoud, circa 1998 (Box 10)
    - Essay for Claude Royet-Journoud, Fall 1998 (Box 10)
    - Summer 1999, Poems - summer of Ma's death (Box 10)
    - Ma and Me and Olmstead, possible new, 1999 (Box 10)
    - Summer 2000 inc. interview work with Cole Swenson for a Conjunctions interview (Box 10)
    - Work on Conjunctions interview [with Cole Swenson], 7 (Box 10)
    - [Conjunctions] interview [with Cole Swenson] as I Wish It, 2000 (Box 10)
    - New Work, 2000 (Box 10)
    - Current, 2000 (Box 10)